Hey Jo, congratulations. Uh just let me
know what interaction you might have had
with the Bucks and and just your
reaction to coming to Tampa Bay.
Certainly a a franchise that your
family's familiar with.
>> Yeah, no doubt. I mean, it was it was a
great visit being to meet that staff,
even at the combine, having my visits
with them. So, you know, just knowing
that coaching staff, especially a lot of
the guys on the coaching staff who I've
known either for a long time or, you
know, they had known my dad and then
especially just I lived in Tampa for a
little bit when my dad played for them.
So, kind of already knowing about not
only just the culture, but you know,
Bucks football and being down there when
I was younger. So, you know, I'm just
excited to be able to get down there,
get to work with all those guys, my
linebackers, coach, and just the rest of
guys on that roster.
>> Just tell us what you think your
strengths are as a linebacker. What do
you do best at the position? Yeah, I
think without a doubt when it comes to
my strengths, it's obviously going to be
physicality. I think as that that
position that's a big thing just for me,
just how I was brought up. But
definitely physicality, my instincts to
be able to play my brain, trying to put
myself ahead of plays, and then just
being a leader, be able to communicate,
be a tone setter. You know, I think I'm
gonna be a player that not only is going
to be able to just do that, but also be
productive out there in all phases of
the game and be able to just, you know,
be someone that guys can look at and be
an alpha, be a leader, be a green dot
guy, and just to be able to look at to
be not only great football player, but a
great locker room guy, someone that's
going to put the team before himself.
>> Jo, congratulations. What do you know
about uh what do you know about Taco
Bell's defense?
>> Yeah, they like the blitz, man. They
like the blitz to get after it, man. and
they play some good defense, hard-nosed
defense. And just talking to him, man,
it's it's a great scheme, great system
be able to fit in and, you know, they're
going to allow you to be able to show
and just showcase everything you can do
as a linebacker from all over. And I I
love that, you know, love what he's been
doing down there, man. And just been
knowing him for, you know, a long time.
>> Josiah, congratulations. You went to a
Clemson camp with Troy Bulls a couple
years ago. You also know Mike Caldwell
back when your dad played in
Philadelphia. just talk about those
unique connections that you have to the
franchise.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Just knowing, you know,
Coach Bose from when I did the camp with
his son and just knowing him ever since
then, just the interactions with him.
So, that was great just being when I met
him then and um he just when he knew my
dad and Coach Cwell and his family just
just being family friends with them for
so long and knowing them when my dad
both our parents play together. So, it
was really cool just to be not only just
meet with them, but just to be a full
circle moment of just all this time
that's passed and just know each other
not only this long, but you know,
finally seeing each other.
>> Josiah, you played basically two years
of college football as a starter. Just
want to ask you what would need the
confidence to to know you could go to
the next level and be drafted as high as
you were a year and play well as a pro.
>> Yeah, I think for me it was like, you
know, when you come to the I feel like
it's the best competition when you go to
the SEC and I feel like you're able to
go dominate. You know, I feel like it's
the closest thing next to going into the
NFL and I felt ready. I feel ready to go
and just I feel like God was leading me
in that direction and praying about it
and just had blessed opportunity just to
be able to come out and, you know, just
trusting him and how my process went and
I knew I feel like I was ready and
capable of just being able to go to that
next level just not only play physically
but also mentally.
>> You've you've been lauded for your uh
role in disruption and, you know, run
seven skills as a linebacker. uh what
kind of skills go into helping you do
that and um how did you develop those
skills and kind of get the instincts for
that type of thing in the game?
>> Yeah, no doubt. I mean, a lot of it is
just God-given instincts and just the
talent ability that he's blessed me with
to allow me to be able to use to have my
dad in my life, you know, to be helped
me from a young age how to use those
things to grow up and just know how to
be not only a professional but to play
this position. There's a lot that comes
with it and a lot of behind the scenes
that you got to put into it that a lot
of people don't see. So, a lot of that
he's built just built up in me just
guiding me, showing me. So, um, you
know, there's a lot there's a lot with
it. So, I think, uh, my strengths and
just everything that comes with it is
something that's just been molded and
branded in me since I was born.
>> Desiah Bullzaps a lot of as linebackers
going downhill blitzing is something
you're really comfortable with.
Obviously, you're a beast against the
run, but as far as coverage dropping
back, what's your comfortability there?
It's something that obviously, you know,
it's something you can improve as as you
get into the next level, but what's your
comfortability there?
>> Yeah, no doubt. I think um you know be
able to showcase everything and I think
when I get within that scheme of
coaching staff uh I'm very comfortable
when it comes to like you know coverage
and those aspects of whatever they're
asking me to do and at this point in my
career being able to touch all those
aspects of coverage or play call and
defensive scheme. So I think when I be
go there, man, just the not only the
coaches I have with me, but it'll
showcase to my game and you know, not
only will they see it, but the whole NFL
will see it and be to show them that not
only I'm a complete player, but the
whole NFL.
>> Josiah, there's not many people that can
say they're the son of an NFL linebacker
and also the brother of an NFL
linebacker. For you, how has that shaped
just your football journey uh growing up
in college?
Yeah, it showed me so much from a young
age, you know, kind of seeing my dad as
dad and then growing up, you know,
learning more about, you know, what that
last name meant, you know, having him
as, you know, not as a coach, um, as a
father, but someone that played in NFL
at a high level and then a brother that
was really good and then ultimately it's
playing right now in NFL. So, you know,
it was a lot of pressure maybe when I
was younger, but I learned, you know,
you never embrace it, you always be
running from it. So, I always learn how
to embrace it, put a chip on my
shoulder, and I think it's also made me
into the player I am today because they
also helped me. they, you know, poured
into me, you know, be to get to me this
point as well. And, you know, just
blessed and thankful to God that, you
know, not only they in my life, but, you
know, they were a positive influence and
people I look up to and really lean on
not only for advice just for football,
but just in life. So,
>> you mentioned the uh, you know,
leadership traits that you bring in that
linebacker room that the Bucks have just
lost the big one in LeBron. So you just
kind of think that line of room and and
trying to make impact maybe as leader as
well.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, the Bucks lost a
great leader, a guy that, you know, I
think should be in the Hall of Fame and
someone I grew up just, you know,
watching and really just really
respected his game, the way he played,
especially as long as he did. And, you
know, to come in as a young guy and be
able to show guys that, you know, I'm
ready to go. I'm ready to work, you
know, and just be to come in and be, you
know, be myself, be my authentic self,
not trying to be, you know, something
I'm not. And um just show that I can be
a leader, you know, in my own way. And
to come in, step in and be someone that
they look at, you know, even if I'm
being, you know, just turned 21, that,
you know, I'm a leader, I can vocalize
and be I'm going to go out there and
make productive plays and they can look
at as an alpha and as a leader, you
know, someone that they can trust and
respect at the same time. ultimately
>> just when when you look at current NFL
linebackers when you're watching Kate,
are there guys that that you like you
like to emulate that have similar body
types, strength, skill sets to what you
have?
>> Um yeah, I mean there's always, you
know, my favorite Fred whenever catches
games, you know, just watching good
linebacker play. Me, I just like seeing
good linebacker play, you know, um just
across the league. So, I think there's a
lot of good linebackers cross the league
that give some really good take, you
know, from week to week or just
throughout the season, you know, and but
for me, I never really had anybody
really just say, "Hey, I just put my
game after him, you know. I think my dad
is always number one because that's my
dad and he played and I'm always going
to take a big portion from his game."
So, um especially my brother, too. But I
think, you know, a lot of things I work
on as a player and things I do, uh, you
know, you don't see too often, uh,
especially maybe nowadays. Um, so I'm
trying to just bring, you know, not only
just physicality back, but bring out not
only old school but new school feel
back, bringing that dominant, you know,
force and just, you know, when when they
see the Bucks defense, you know, I want
people to feel that defense, you know,
feel that front seven all around cuz,
you know, I don't want to just be one
play. I want to be the whole defense,
just be a bunch of dogs out there.
>> What do you know about the Bucks first
round draft pick Ruben Bane? How excited
are you to kind of come in and be part
of that rookie class with him?
>> Man, excited. I was uh I was able to
talk with him um a while back when we
were on the same visit together in
Cincinnati. Great dude. You know, I know
he's fired up. He's got a chip on my
shoulder like I got a chip on my
shoulder. We're just ready to just go
show not only just, you know, Bucks
Nation, but the NFL, you know, the whole
world, you know, what we can do. Um and
just, you know, just grateful too for
the opportunity be to go there and be to
show teams.
>> What did uh Todd Bull say if anything
about your opportunity? I mean obvious
you a green duck guy. Is that the kind
of role you think you can step in and
handle right away as a as a 21-year-old?
>> Yeah. You know, just talking with coach
Bose and just, you know, um basically,
you know, let me know like, you know,
obviously, you know, you see they lost
Devonte David and losing a great leader,
you know, guy that was a green dot
that's been there and played a long
time. and that's a role to be able to
step in and know something they always
ask me and that's something I've done
since a young age of someone that's
called be able to make plays to call
plays and everything like that. So, you
know, I'm very comfortable being able to
do that um and being a step into that
role and to you know do it um you know
to the best of my ability and knowing
that you know they I feel like they'll
be happy with me being stepping into
that position. And being 21 years old
after playing two seasons of college
football, do you feel like you're
scratching the surface of your potential
and what you could be?
>> So, without a shadow of doubt, I'm only
scratching my surface. You know, um, you
know, I only played two seasons and was
able to play one season with Missou
just, you know, of just getting there
with a different scheme. And I'm just
scratching the surface. And once people
find out and then see what God put on
the inside of me or what I can truly do
as a all-around linebacker, um you know,
man, I they over know, but I I can I can
only show you better. I can tell you. So
that's all I really tell people, man. I
can only show you better. I can tell
you. So I'm just let time do its thing.
And when I get there, just put my head
down, go grind, get to work, and just
try to be the best me I can possibly be
that God made me to be. What's your
message to Bucks fans who are watching
this and excited to have you in Tampa?
>> Man, one thing you're going to get a
player that's not only just committed
and selfless, but is going to be a
physical player that is going to come in
and just try to, you know, bring a Super
Bowl. That's my ultimate goal to bring a
Super Bowl to Bucks Nation. Try to be
the best version I can be for not only
just Bucks Nation, but for my team, my
coaches, my family, God. And, you know,
I just want to come in and just give
y'all everything I got every single day.
And uh try to just come in and be
myself. you know, you guys lost a great
one. I want to come in and try to be
even better than that and exceed that.
And man, he was he was a great person
just to be able to watch and especially
as long as he was there.
>> Thank you. Congratulations.
>> See you.